hi this video explains what business
Central Partners should consider when
designing the onboarding experience when
customizing the welcome banner and user
checklists it's a clip from a launch
minute video for 2023 release Wave 2 but
it's equally relevant today let's turn
it over to Sarah who'll tell us more
about it so now we have established that
when the users arrived at the role
Center in business Central the banner is
there to greet them and to really um be
this
entrance um for where to get
started so when creating content for the
banner keep in mind to keep the welcome
message short and clear and to make the
user really discover and want to follow
that call to
action and once the user clicks the
action in this case show
demurs the checklist shows up in the
banner providing overview and structure
of the relevant activities guiding the
users successfully through discovering
key values in business
Central so as son said the checklist is
really the main onboarding piece that
allows you to surface the different
onboarding components and orchestrate
what the customer goes through but just
remember that the user can move and
navigate freely between the tasks and
might even skip some of them to revisit
them later so you can't always guarantee
that they follow the order that you
decided and also consider the difference
between a checklist for the aval trial
situation where um you want the you you
want the users to experience the um
value propositions and the goto live
checklist where the purpose is to get
business Central set up in the perfect
way for the
customer so when putting together the
checklist for the evaluation and trial
keep in mind that the customer's
patience and maybe even time is really
short that's why we also have the little
minute indicator on every task so you
want to put together the checklist for
evaluation that is really short and with
as little friction as possible so it's
important um to try to avoid complex
tasks to not to for the users to not
feel
stuck maybe start with a smaller task
first that gives them an understanding
of business Central as well as a feeling
of success and progression in the
checklist because we know that that
builds confidence in users to um go and
explore
further and also consider if you can use
a good mix of content as turn said so
not have all videos or all Spotlight
tours but a good mix uh creates a more
engaging
experience now the checklist used for go
live has a slightly different
goal now it's actually about setting
business Central and the user up for
doing work and the checklist items can
be a little more involved related to
setting up users
permissions and so on and in that case
it's really important that you consider
the user's role and make the che
checklist role
oriented so um if a user isn't
responsible for permissions showing a
task about permissions would not be a
good choice also keep setup as short as
possible pre-configure as much as much
as you
can um what we have found also is that
if you have too many checklist items um
it doesn't work so well the checklist is
designed for five six maybe seven and if
you have more than that you can wrap
those up in an assisted setup list as s
showed and and guide the users that way
to learn more visit aka.ms slbc
onboarding thank you for watching
[Music]